so we want to solve for x in this
triangle we're going to use the exterior
angle theorem
so if we call this a this b and this c
it is always true that a will equal b
plus c and these are the two angles that
are opposite
of this one so let's fill in for a b and
c a was 3x plus 2
b is x plus 25 and c is x plus 17.
i put the parentheses there so we could
see each of the angles x plus
x is 2x and 25 plus 17 is 42.
so we have an x on both sides of the
equation we want to subtract the smaller
one over to the other side
3x minus 2x is x bring down the 2 2x
minus 2x goes away
so we just have a 42 on this side so
subtract 2 from both sides
42 minus 2 is 40 for the right hand side
and that's the answer the question x
equals 40.
so we use the exterior angles theorem to
solve this
comment on this video for what you'd
like me to solve next and i'll talk to
you guys soon
bye